我刚才走进浴室  竟然看见凯西光着身体
I just walked in the bathroom and saw Kathy naked
简直是种折磨
It was like torture.
如果你曾当过战俘  才会惊讶的知道什么叫"折磨"
Y'know if we ever go to war and you're captured, you're in for a big surprise.
情况变得越来越糟
It just keeps getting worse and worse!
你知道么  够糟了  我居然爱上我室友的女朋友了
Y'know? I mean it's bad enough that I'm in love with my roommate's girlfriend
而且  我觉得她也知道
which by the way,I think she knows.
每次我们共处一室  空气就很诡异紧张
Because every time we're in the room together there's this weird like energy between us.
更叫我疯狂的是  我觉得她也喜欢我
And call me crazy, but I think she likes me too.
现在我又看到她的裸体
And now I have seen her naked.
我是说  至少看见她穿衣服的时候
I mean at least when I've seen her with clothes on,
我能想像她的身体是被树皮什么的给盖住的
...I could imagine her body was like covered in boles or something.
结果没有  她是光着身子的
But there are no boles. She's smooth.
光着的
Smooth!
啊哦
Wow...
他刚才那样子坐着都走光了
Could everyone totally see up his robe?
天啊  我的天啊
Oh, my God. Yeah.
《老友记》  第四季  第07集   钱德横刀夺爱
Friends S04E07  The One Where Chandler Crosses a Line
（主演：詹妮弗·安妮斯顿）
（主演：柯特妮·考克斯）
（主演：丽莎·库卓）
（主演：马特·勒布朗）
（主演：马修·派瑞）
（主演：大卫·修蒙）
拿去
Here you go.
好  我待会打给你
Great. so I'll call you later.
嘿  嘿  那是谁
Hey, hey. Who was that?
那是凯希  我们晚上要约会
Casey. We're going out tonight.
约会  哇  哇
Going out? huh? Wow! Wow!
你跟凯西分手了  真可惜
So things didn't work out with Kathy, huh? Bummer.
没有啊  我们很好
No, things are fine with Kathy.
我跟她吃饭之前要先跟凯希吃
I'm having a late dinner with her tonight, right after my early dinner with Casey.
什么
What? Yeah.
是的  是的  更夸张的是我刚刚一个人吃了一整个披萨
Yeah-yeah. And the craziest thing is that I just ate a whole pizza by myself!
导演：凯文S布莱特
慢着  你要跟凯西约会
Wait...  You're going out with Kathy.
对  你怎么变得颠三倒四的
Yeah. Why are you getting so upset
我是颠三倒四
Well, I'm upset...
全是因为你
...for you.
我是说  没完没了和各色美貌女子上床  恐怕很难满足你
I mean,having sex with an endless line of beautiful women must be very unfulfilling for you.
那又怎样  又不是只有我们才这么干
What's the big deal? It's not like we're exclusive.
听着  乔伊
Look, Joey.
凯西很明显无法满足你的感情需求
Kathy is clearly not fulfilling your emotional needs.
但是凯希…
But Casey...
老实说  我只看到过她的后脑勺
I mean granted I only saw the back of her head,
但是我感觉得到她聪明风趣
But I got this sense that she's smart and funny...
而且很在乎你
...and gets you.
你真能从后脑勺看出这么多东西
You got all that from the back of her head?
好吧  听着  我想你真的应该安定下来了
All right look, I think it's time for you to settle down.
做个选择  选条道路([e lein])
Y'know? Make a choice, pick a lane.
谁是"伊莱恩"([i'lein])
Who's Elaine?
小泰山东尼
"Little, tiny Tarzan,
用鼻毛荡来荡去  悠闲的荡着秋千...
swinging on a nose hair. Swinging with the greatest of ease..."
该死的  现在我不知道该怎么接下一段
Darn it! Now,I don't know who to get to the next verse.
你可以唱
Oh, you could just go uh,
"很悠闲呀
"greatest of ease...
BAH-bah-bha-bhannn
BAH-bah-bha-bhannn."
然后继续下去
Then go right into it.
也对  我喜欢
Yeah, ooh, I like that!
等一下  你是怎么知道的
How do you know about "ba-ma-na-ma-na-ma"?
你知道  我过去也经常弹奏乐器
Well umm, y'know, I used to play.
对了  对了  是电子琴
Oh yeah, that's right, the keyboards, huh?
高中只是玩玩  到大学时就完全地沉迷其中了
Yeah, just a little in high school, but then I really got into it in college.
我是说  我那是真的找到属于我的声音
I mean that's-that's when I really found my sound.
我把果汁喷出来了  但是值得
Oh God! Orange juice just came out of my nose, but it was totally worth it.
天哪
Oh, my God.
我已完全忘记你的那种"声音"了  是啊
I completely forgot about your sound. Yeah.
他常把自己锁在地下室好几个小时
He used to lock himself in the basement for hours.
谁也不准听那个"声音"
No one was every allowed to hear, "The Sound."
我想听那个 "声音"
I want to hear "The Sound."
真的  不行  我很久没弹了
Really? No. I mean, nah, I haven't played in so long,
那是很私密的东西
and-and, well it's-it's really personal stuff, y'know?
来嘛  演奏你那恐怖的音乐吧  "小孩"
Come on, play that funky music white boy.
是啊   不行啦
Yeah, boy. No, you guys,
我的电子琴早就在我那  收起来了  好吧  我去拿
I mean my keyboards are all the way up in ... Oh Yeah, okay.
可以了
Okay, guys.
你竟然又找出来了
All right. Bring it on, you.
我们开始吧
Here we go.
你们要知道  我从未...从未在别人面前表演过我的作品
Y'know, I've-I've never played my stuff for anyone before,
所以你们得清楚一件很重要的事
so it's important that-that you understand
我将和大家交流
... it's about communicating...
非常私人的感情
...very private emotions.
你们还得知道
Y'know, umm,
你们得...呃  你们要思考  我的作品
you should-you should think of umm, my work...
就像是是无言的诗
...as wordless sound poems.
我还要说...  噢  天呀  快弹
That's what I'm.... Oh.my God! Play!
听啊  简直太...
Boy, that was-that was, umm...
太棒了
...terrific.
真的是  棒极了
Really, bitchin'!
哇  实在是太
Wow, it was so -- wow!
真的吗  我是说  真的么
Really?! I mean, really?!!
对  你应该到公众场合来弹
Yeah. I mean, you should play in public.
谢谢你们  这真是…
Wow, thanks, you guys. That's...ohhh,
我想再为大家演奏另一首曲子
I wanna, I wanna play you another piece!
啊哦
Umm! Uh-oh!
直升机音效在另一张磁片里  我去拿  我马上回来
I left my uh, helicopter sounds on another disk. I'll be right back! Okay?
这太好了  我是说  我是如此
This is so nice.  I'm -- I am so...
幸好老爸的地下室有隔音层
Oh God bless my dad sound proofing the basement!
我不敢相信  他竟然用弹奏这种曲子的手指抚摸过我
I can't believe I ever let him touch me with those fingers.
你们在说什么  我好喜欢
What are you guys talking about? I loved it.
太动人了
It was so moving.
而且它还同你们平常听的东西完全不一样
Oh, plus it's just, it's so different from the stuff you usually hear.
你是说音乐吗
You mean music?
我知道你在想什么
Yeah, I know what you're thinkin'!
你的胸部也很结实而且诱人
Yes, yes, your breasts are just as firm and juicy.
请进
Come in.
天哪
Hey.
那是《海滩游侠》吗
Oh, God. Is that Baywatch?
对  是的  但我只是看看演员表而已
Uh yes, but uh, I just watch it for the articles.
乔伊在吗
So is Joey around?
不在  还没回来  但是他再过几分钟就回来了
No-no, he's not back yet, but he'll be here any minute.
先请进  坐一会吧  船头还是船尾
So uh, come on in. Have a seat. Bow or stern?
我无所谓坐哪  你呢
I uh, don't really have a preference. You?
我喜欢后面
I like it in the stern.
船尾
Of the boat.
听着  是我  我和凯希在回来的路上出了状况
Hey, It's me. Listen Casey and I were on our way back and had a little car trouble.
怎么了  我们在专属车道上抛锚了
What happened? We broke down on the Parkway,
我得走回去找一些变速液
so I have to walk back and get some transmission fluid.
听着  请告诉凯西  抱歉  我会尽快赶回来的
And listen，you please tell Kathy that I'am sorry I'll be there as soon as I can.
你怎么不自己说  因为我只有一刻钟  而且我想投币时间快要...
Why can't you tell her? 'Cause I only have one quarter, and I think my time is about to--
乔伊  乔伊
Joey? Joey?
嗯
Yeah?
我以为你时间不够了...
I thought your time ran out.
我也以为  看来还有一点…
Me too, but I guess I do have a couple of more --
是乔伊  他说他很抱歉  他得迟点到了
Uhh, that was Joey. He's running a little late, he says he's sorry.
所以我想  现在只有你和我
So I guess it's just uh, you and me then.
好
Ok
噢  我想也是
Okay. Yeah, I think it is.
那么今天你都干了些什么呢
So what'd you do today?
我今天要去理发的
Oh, I had an appointment to get my haircut...
你的发型很好看  后来没去成
Oh, it looks great! ...and then it got canceled.
我可以帮你剪
Well, I could cut it.
真的吗  你真的会
Really?! You do that?
是的  我会理  我从我姑妈的狗儿理发店学的 怎么样
Yeah, I do. Of course, I learned at my aunt's dog grooming shop, but hey, what do you say?
狗儿理发店
Dog grooming huh?
好吧  只要别把我的"尾巴"搞得太脂粉气了
Okay, just don't make my tail too poofy.
你的发质真的很好
You have really great hair.
噢  谢谢  我自己种出来的
Well, thanks. I grow it myself.
你知道么  乔伊的发质也很好
Y'know who also has great hair is Joey!
对  乔伊的发质很好
Yes! Yeah! Joey has great hair!
差不多完了  帮你清理一下脖子上的头发屑
Umm, I'm basically done here. Just let me get this off your neck.
你在干什么
What-what 'cha doin'?
检查看着是不是比较自然
Checking to see if it's even.
怎么样
'Kay.
看来没问题
Looks good.
噢  是电话  电话在响
Oh the phone! The phone's making sounds.
哈罗  老兄  是我
Hello. Hey, dude, it's me.
是乔伊
Hey, it's Joey.
听着  抱歉啊  看来我被困在这里了
Listen uh, I'm really sorry, it looks like I'm gonna be stuck here for a while.
我弄到变速液了  但是要加时
I got the transmission fluid, but when I went to put it in the car,
却发现变速器不见了
the transmission wasn't there!
什么  可能是在前几个路口就掉了
What? Yeah, it must've fallen out a few blocks back.
听到异响  我还以为撞到了狗
I just figured we hit a dog.
好吧
Okay.
请凯西来听  我想跟她道歉
Listen uh, could you put Kathy on, I wanna apologize.
好
Oh yeah man.
乔伊
Joey.
嗨
Hey...
噢  一切都还好  不用为我担心
No, it's fine. Don't worry about it.
不用道歉  不要紧的
Yeah-no, stop apologizing, it's okay.
好  明天再联络
Yeah! I'll talk to you tomorrow.
我想  我可能得走了
I should uh, probably go. Yeah.
呃  是的  没错
Yeah. Yes! Yeah.
我忘了带皮包
I forgot my purse.
噢
Oh...
不  我是真的忘了带皮包  不  不  不
No, I really did forget my purse.No-no-no
不  不  不  不  这太差劲了  太差  太差劲了
No-no-no-no, this is bad! It's bad! This is bad!
太糟糕了
Horrible!
等等  你是说吻还是状况
Wait the uh, the kiss or the situation?
不  不  不  这个吻很棒
No-no-no, the kiss was good.
不  就是这个吻太可怕了  是的  我们应该
No, but that's bad! Ooh! Yes! Okay! Here's what we do,
应该当什么都没发生过  什么
we-we forget it happened. What?
好吧  我们得隐藏我们的感情
Okay, we-we swallow our feelings.
即使这样会痛苦一辈子  听起来好些么
Even if it means we're unhappy forever. Sound good?
你真的做得到
Can you really do that?
我不得不  他是我最好的朋友
I have to. He's my best friend.
而你在跟他交往
And you're seeing him.
钱德  我很喜欢乔伊
Chandler, I like Joey a lot.
但是跟你…
But with you...
不  不  别说了
No, don't. Don't, see?
你会把我搞乱  我已经开始渴望了
You're getting me confused. I'm starting to yearn.
对不起
I'm sorry.
要是你想假装没事  我可以试试看
If you want to pretend that nothing happened, I can try.
我们非这么做不可
I think we have to.
好吧
Okay.
再见  再见
Bye. Bye.
你是不是还没走
Are you still out there?
没有
No.
通电中...
Electrifying
加重  时间  时间  时间
Emphatic time-time-time...
你们知道么  过去三个街口有一家"星巴克"
Y'know, there's a Starbucks about three blocks down.
多么有灵韵呀  看他啊  听他演奏
It's so inspired! Look at him! Look at him go!
谢谢大家  大家  大家...
Thank you guys-guys-guys...
接着不是该你吗
Hey, aren't you up next?
噢  不  我今晚不想弹了  为什么
Oh no, I'm not playing tonight. Why not?
我不能接在罗斯后面
I can't follow Ross.
就像披头士演完了
It'd be like those bicycle ridding chimps
接着让骑自行车的黑猩猩演奏一样  不行
that followed The Beetles. No....
菲比  罗斯简直太糟糕了
Phoebe. Ross sucks.
菲比  他把客人都吓跑了
Phoebe, the place has emptied because of him.
天哪  在他自己的时代都没有人欣赏他
Oh my God, he's not even appreciated in his own time.
我巴不得能跟他一样的寂寞
I'd give anything to not be appreciated in my own time.
好  菲比…
Okay. Umm, Phoebe,
你也很差劲
You suck too.
没错  菲比
Yeah, Phoebe.
你也差到一定份上了
You're awful.
你们俩
You guys.
你们俩都很差
You suck too.
天哪  简直无法相信  我又把自己锁在外面了
Aww man! I can't believe I locked myself out again!
等一下  老兄
Hang on, buddy.
天哪  出了什么事
Oh my God! What happened here?
这都是你买的  我想是的
Did you do all this? I sure did.
为什么  我只是认为  为我的朋友做点事  让我感觉很好
Why? Well, I just thought it'd make me feel good to do something nice for my friend.
你简直太不可思议了
Well, you're amazing.
不  不  不  这些东西才不可思议呢
Oh no-no-no. This is amazing.
凭空冒出来的电视
A TV as if it appears from nowhere!
简直象做梦一样  老兄
That's the dream! Man,
你哪来这么多钱
how did you afford this stuff?
我都29了  还存那么多钱干什么
Well, y'know I'm 29. I mean who needs a savings account.
你是世界上最棒的朋友
Oh, you are the best friends anyone has ever had.
那可不一定
Oh, I don't know.
不  不  不  你是的
Oh-no-no-no, you are!
你买这些东西  还给我忠告
You do this, you give me the great advice,
听着  昨天你让我只对一个女孩子好
and hey listen, I was thinking about what you said yesterday about focusing on one woman,
我决定照做
I'm gonna do that.
是不是打算和凯希
You mean with Casey.
不  不  不  我想继续跟凯西交往下去  她很酷
No-no-no, I think I'm gonna see how things go with Kathy. She's pretty cool.
或者凯希  不  不  凯西
Or Casey. No-no, Kathy.
凯希也行
Could be Casey.
不  不  凯西
No-no, Kathy.
考虑一下凯希
Consider Casey.
你知道我怎么想么  看来有人喜欢凯希了
Y'know what I think? I think somebody's got a little crush on Casey.
要不要我撮合你们俩呢  你怎么想
How 'bout I fix you two up? What do you think?
那我的生活终于可以踏入正轨了
That all the pieces of my life are falling right into place.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
你太棒了  你真的  真的很棒
You were really great! You were really, really great!
谢谢  谢谢
Oh, thanks, thanks.
摩妮卡说你以后都不再想演奏了
So Monica tells me that uh, you don't want to play anymore
因为我...和我的才华
because me....and y'know my talent.
是真的吗
Is that true?
哦  大概吧  是的  菲比
Well, kind of, yeah. Pheebs...
是的  但我无法  我很想保持乐观无所谓的态度
Yeah, I-I can't --I mean y'know I was trying to be really y'know okay and upbeat about it...
但是在你的才华面前  我自惭形秽
...I just -- I feel so dwarfed by your musical gift. I...
但是…
See, but...
菲比  这和我演奏的初衷完全相反了
Pheebs that-that is the exact opposite intent of my music.
你知道  我的音乐是要鼓舞人心的
Y'know my music is-is meant to inspire,
如果这样反而挫伤了你
If it bothers you this much...
那我以后  就不再演奏了
...then I won't play anymore.
不  不  不  千万不要
Oh no. No-no-no, don't do that!
如果离开你的音乐  我怎么能活得下去呢
How could I live with myself if I knew I was depriving the world of your music.
好吧
Yeah, okay.
嘿  钱德  看到新家具了  非常漂亮
Hey Chandler! Saw the new furniture. Very nice.
乔伊有你这个男朋友真好
Yeah! Joey has the best boyfriend ever!
我吻了凯西
I kissed Kathy.
什么  你是说真的
What? Are you serious?
乔伊知道吗  不知道
Does Joey know? No.
你们认为有没有可能  他能谅解吗
Is there anyway, anyway you think he'll understand this?
你显然还没有深入了解你的室友
You obviously haven't screwed over a lot of your friends.
这正是让我们都敬佩不已的
Which we all appreciate.
不  最可悲的是  如果你在亲她之前告诉乔伊你的感受
No the-the sad thing is, if you had told him how you felt before you kissed her,...
乔伊肯定会把她让给你的
...knowing Joey, he probably just would've just stepped aside.
别  不要告诉我  不要告诉我  那是真的
Oh, don't say that! Don't say that. That's not true. Is it?
我想可能  是真的  他爱你
I think maybe, yeah. He loves you.
那你们怎么不告诉我
Then why didn't you tell me to do that?
我跟菲比聊过
Well, I said-I said something to Phoebe.
对  我觉得这是个好主意
Yeah! No, that's right. And I thought it was a really good idea.
我就知道  我还记得  我也记得你告诉过我
I know, I remember that! I remember you did.
天哪  我该怎么办
God!! What am I gonna do?!
钱德  你得告诉他
Well, Chandler, you're gonna have to tell him.
为什么  为什么非得告诉他
Why?! Why do I have to tell him?!
因为你必须这么做  是的  我知道
Because you do. Yeah, I know.
我为此写首曲子  能不能让你好过点
Hey, would it be okay if I wrote a song about this.
嘿  嘿
Hey. Hey.
要不要"茴香玛格丽特"鸡尾酒
Sambuca Margarita?
那是什么东西
It that a real thing?
哦   我们只剩茴香味力娇酒   所以就有“茴香玛格丽特”鸡尾酒了
Well, we only had sambuca, so it is now.
听着  乔伊
Listen, Joe.
我必须  必须要跟你谈谈了
I-I need to, I need to talk to you about something.
什么事
What's up?
是凯西的事
It's-it's about Kathy.
我喜欢她
I like her.
事实上  我非常喜欢她
I like her a lot, actually.
真的么
You do? Yeah.
那你现在的时机正好
Well, you're timing couldn't be better.
她现在不是我的女朋友了
She's not my girlfriend anymore.
什么
What?
哦  她跟我分手了
Yeah, she broke up with me.
什么时候的事
Oh uh, when?
就刚才  表演课后
Just now, after acting class.
开始我以为她只是在表演某个场景  我还叫大家来看
At first I thought she was doing some kind of scene, that's why I let people watch.
哦  太可惜了  你还好吗
Oh man, I am so sorry. Are, are you okay?
不太好  但我现在没事了  你喜欢她
Well, I've been better. But, I'm all right. So you like her huh?
对  但是我可以算了
Yes, but I-I uh, don't have too.
不  不  我没事的
No-no-no, no it's uh, it's okay.
真的  对
Yeah? Yeah.
你知道为什么  因为你先来告诉我
You know why? 'Cause you came to me first.
我就知道这么干没错
Well, I thought that would be the best thing to do.
但是  你听着  恐怕你还得努把力
But hey, listen just so you know, you might have you're work cut out for you.
我跟她谈的时候  觉得她好像喜欢另一个人  所以..
'Cause when I talked to her, I kinda got the feeling that she's into some other guy. So...
你知道么  这正是我想跟你谈的事情
See uh, that's-that's actually what I wanted to talk to you about.
我想  我知道那个人是谁
I-I think I know who the other guy is.
是谁
Who?
是我
It's me.
我就是那个别人
I'm the other guy.
什么
What?
是的  昨晚你回来迟了  凯西和我聊了起来
Yeah, I mean when you were late last night, Kathy and I got to talking, ...
事情演变到后来就…
...and one thing to another and...
就什么  你跟她上床了
And what? Did you sleep with her?
没有  没有  我只是吻了她
No! No! No! I just kissed her.
什么   那更糟糕
What? That's even worse.
怎么会更糟  我不知道  但那都不行
How is that worse? I don't know! But it's the same!
听着  我很抱歉  但我没办法  我已经深深爱上了她
Look, I'm sorry! But there's nothing I can do, I think I'm in love with her!
谁管你
Who cares?
你背着我乱来  我绝不会那样对你
You went behind my back? I'd never do that to you.
你说得对  我无话可说  我太过份了
You're right, I have no excuses! I was totally over the line.
过份  你过份过..过了这么多
Over the line?! You-you're-you're so far past the line,
甚至看不到线在哪
that you-you can't even see the line!
你根本就没管那条线
The line is a dot to you!
没错
Yes.
没错  我也知道这很糟糕  你要相信我
Yes! Right! And I feel horrible. You have to believe me!
所以你买了这么多家具
Is that why you bought all this stuff!
你知道吗
Well, y'know what
我不会再看你的电视
I will not watch your TV.
我不听你的音响
I won't listen to your stereo.
烤面包机里有一个面包我也不吃  知道为什么
and there's a cinnamon raisin loaf in the new bread maker that I'm not gonna eat! You know why?!
因为…
Probably because...
因为它被你的背叛弄脏了
Because it's all tainted with your betrayal.
从现在起  房子对我来说就是空着的
From now on this apartment is empty for me!
而且也不会跟你一起玩了
And I'm not happy about you either.
跟你说一声
And just so you know...
那个面包是为你烤的
...I made that bread for you.
天哪  他江郎才尽了  灵气荡然无存了
Oh my God, he's lost it. He's totally lost it.
什么
What?
菲比  他的音乐本来就没有可取之处
Phoebe, his music could not get any worse.
地下室的老鼠听了都去上吊了
There are rats in the basement that are hanging themselves.
谢谢  谢谢
Thank you. Thanks.
是的  我才思枯竭了
Yeah, I lost it.
我不会再演奏了  你愿意
Y'know, I'm not gonna play anymore, Would you...
继续演奏下去么
Can you finish my set?
接着上台  可以
After that? Yeah!
我是说我愿意尽力
No, I mean, if I can help.
好像我真的没灵感了似的
Yeah, like I could lose it.
什么  我是有意弹得佷差
What? I played bad on purpose guys.
是么  你这段时间一直是故意  弹得这么难听
Okay, so you were trying to play bad this whole time.
呃  不  只是刚刚这最后一首
Yeah. no, just that last song.